CONTACT

N: 55 1935 9021 C: Dylancastt@outlook.com

PORTFOLIO LINK

Link: Portfolio-Dylan.html



PROFESSIONAL OBJECTIVE

Applying all the knowledge gained from my professional career and work experience, as well as life experience, to implement strategies aimed at optimizing resources and driving the development of the company and the environment. Striving to become a specialist in automation and data analysis

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Inglés-Intermediate (B2)
- Excel- Advanced • Power BI-Advanced
- Alteryx Advanced
- Python Intermediate
- SQL Intermediate
- Visual Studio Code Intermediate
- Tableu Intermediate
 SAP Intermediate
- Minitab Intermediate
- Project Intermediate
- R Basic/Intermediate
- SAS- Basic/Intermediate
- MATLAB Basic/Intermediate
- SolidWorks Basic
- Signavio Basic

CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Tennis
- F1 simracing
- ping pong
- mindfulness

DYLAN JAIR RIVERA CASTAÑEDA

INDUSTRIAL ENGINEER

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

♦ DATA ANALYST CHS | JUL 2023 - CURRENTLY

- Develop and maintain the "DivePort" platform.
- Generate reports for various hospital departments, facilitating data-driven decisionmaking.
- Collaborate in planning the demand for materials and medications.
- Participate in a project to standardize the information managed by the hospital, improving data consistency and accuracy.
- Participate in a project to measure the capacity of hospital equipment and workload across different departments.

♦ BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE INTERN AT VEMO | AUG 2022 - DEC 2022

- Mapped all processes within the Human Resources department.
- Proposed improvements and standardized various processes.
- Automated databases, resulting in over 80% reduction in time spent and cleaned up previous data.
- Created Key Performance Indicators (KPIs) for performance tracking.
- Provided training to staff on best practices in Excel.
- Provided support in various selection processes.

OBOSCH DEMAND PLANNING INTERN | NOV 2021 - AUG 2022

- Creating various reports and automating their processes.
- Monitoring maritime and land shipments.
- Carrying out demand planning for a product line of the company.

PROJECTS

♦ BANORTE | FEB 2023 - MAR 2023

• Create a proposal to reduce employee turnover among Generation Z. This proposal won the campus competition and I can present it to the directors of BANORTE.

O DIGITALENT DEMAND PLANNING UNILEVER SEP 2021 - NOV 2021

- Optimizing the consolidation process through automation of the shape of stocks report, resulting in a 91.6% reduction in time (from 2 hours to 10 minutes).
- Implementing a tool to facilitate opportunity identification by improving stock visualization for enhanced business opportunity detection.

EDUCATION

TECNOLOGICO DE MONTERREY | AUG 2019 - JUN 2023

• I am recently graduated at Tecnológico de Monterrey CEM, and I have a specialization in data analysis. Throughout my life, I have developed values and skills that have helped me successfully complete various projects and complementary activities.

VOLUNTEERING

٥

PREPANET | AUG 2020 - JUN 2021

 Providing tutoring by identifying and addressing individual needs, adapting the methodology, and evaluating learning outcomes to provide constructive feedback.

FORMACIÓN COMPLEMENTARIA

- ♠ CERTIFICACION CAPM | FEB 2023 ABR 2023
- Este curso de Project management es impartido por el Tecnológico de Monterrey